That humble radiant terrific book is now a humble radiant terrific movie.
Charlotte's Web is a family, music, animation film directed by Iwao Takamoto.
Wilbur the pig is scared of the end of the season, because he knows
that come that time, he will end up on the dinner table.
He hatches a plan with Charlotte, a spider that lives in his
pen, to ensure that this will never happen.
Charlotte (voice), played by Debbie Reynolds.
Wilbur (voice), played by Henry Gibson.
Avery Arable (voice), played by Danny Bonaduce.
Goose (voice), played by Agnes Moorehead.
Homer Zuckerman (voice), played by Bob Holt.
Templeton (voice), played by Paul Lynde.
Charlotte's Web is a 1973 American animated musical drama film
based on the 1952 book of the same name by E.
It was produced by Hanna-Barbera Productions and
distributed by Paramount Pictures.
Like the book, it centers on a pig named Wilbur who befriends an intelligent
spider named Charlotte who saves him from being slaughtered.
Directed by Charles A.
Nichols and Iwao Takamoto from a story by Earl Hamner Jr., it stars the voices of Debbie
Reynolds, Paul Lynde, and Henry Gibson, alongside narration by Rex Allen.
It features a score of music and lyrics written by the Sherman Brothers, who had previously written music for
family films like Mary Poppins in 1964, The Jungle Book in 1967, and Chitty Chitty Bang Bang in 1968.
The film premiered at Radio City Music Hall on February 22, 1973, and was
released on March 1 to moderate critical and commercial success.
It is the first of only four Hanna-Barbera films not to be based upon one of
their famous television cartoons, the other three being C.H.O.M.P.S.
in 1979, Heidi's Song in 1982, and Once Upon a Forest in 1993.
The film explores themes of friendship, musical,
anthropomorphism, spider web, talking pig.